<!-- index.xml {% comment %}
*****************************************************************************************
*                            WARNING: DO NOT EDIT THIS FILE                             *
*                                                                                       *
* This file is generated by SUSHI. Any edits you make to this file will be overwritten. *
*                                                                                       *
* To change the contents of this file, edit the original source file at:                *
* genomics-reporting/input/pages/index.xml                                              *
*****************************************************************************************
{% endcomment %} -->
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd">

  <a name="scope"> </a>
  <h3>Scope</h3>
  <p>
A single Adverse Event may need to be reported in multiple ways. Choosing the appropriate form of the reporting is dependent upon workflow patterns. In particular, the implementation guides for Clinical Care adverse events  and Clinical Research adverse events  provide important extensions, value-sets and examples for implementing AdverseEvent.
</p>
  <p>
    This guide, the Clinical Care adverse event Profile implementation guide, is for the clinical care setting. Implementers should use the profile in this guide as a base profile for more specific clinical use cases.
  </p>

  <p>
  Within this guide are some examples. Every effort has been made to capture important details of the use of the AdverseEvent profile. However, some examples may provide only a stub to referenced resources (e.g. instances of Patient Resource will be referenced using logical ids but are not resolvable, implementation of Patient is left for other guidance and is not the subject of this guide). Connectathons are ideal opportunities to create, compare and consider the holistic implementation of all FHIR Resources. And, as mentioned the profile in this guide is meant to be a base to build upon. It is expected that further constraints would be used in IGs for more specific use cases or settings (e.g. US Core).
  </p>


  <!--a name="how to use this guide"> </a>
  <h3>How to Use this Guide</h3> 
  <p>
  This implementation guide is focused on the use of the <a href="StructureDefinition-AdverseEvent-clinical-research.html">AdverseEvent Resource in Clinical Research</a>. When reviewing profiles begin with the snapshot view to understand the entire set of data elements and rules for implementation. The differential does no show elements unchanged from the parent, in the snapshot constraints inherited from the parent are visible. Those new to FHIR should review the Understanding FHIR section below.
  </p-->
  
  <a name="previous"> </a>
  <h3>Previous Specifications</h3>
  <p>
    FHIR STU4 contained a non-normative version of the AdverseEvent Resource. The specification here is based on changes made in R5 and supersedes the use of the R4 Resource.
  </p>
  <!--a name="fhir"> </a>
  <h3>Understanding FHIR</h3>
  <p>
    This implementation guide is based on the HL7 <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}index.html">FHIR</a> standard. It uses terminology, notations and design principles that are specific to FHIR. Before reading this implementation guide, it's important to be familiar with some of the basic principles of FHIR as well as general guidance on how to read FHIR specifications. Readers who are unfamiliar with FHIR are encouraged to read (or at least skim) the following prior to reading the rest of this implementation guide.
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}overview.html">FHIR overview</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}overview-dev.html">Developer's introduction</a>
    </li>
    <li>(or <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}overview-clinical.html">Clinical introduction</a>)</li>
    <li>
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}datatypes.html">FHIR data types</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}terminologies.html">Using codes</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}references.html">References between resources</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}formats.html">How to read resource &amp; profile definitions</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}resource.html">Base resource</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}validation.html">FHIR Validation</a>
    </li>
  </ul-->

  <a name="flexibility"> </a>
  <h3>Extending beyond this Guide</h3>
  <p>
    Implementers should use this guide to AdverseEvent Clinical Care communications in an interoperable way. It is understood that this guide is not complete, and implementers might identify additional concepts and data elements. Please review this guidance for ways to handle those use cases. Additionally, it is recommended that additional Implementation Guides should be adapted from this one as a base for tighter specifications such as in oncology clinical trials.
  </p>

  <a name="acknowledgments"> </a>
  <h3>Acknowledgments</h3>
  <p>
    The Clinical Care Adverse Event Implementation Guide is a product of the <a href="">HL7 Patient Care Work Group</a>. Questions or comments regarding this implementation guide should be directed to Patient Care at <a href="mailto:patientcare@lists.hl7.org">patientcare@lists.hl7.org</a>. 
  </p>
  <p>
    The authors of this guide wish to recognize the following participants who contributed their time and expertise to the continued development of this guide:
  </p>

</div>
